dishonline.com 2011-12-01

# DISH Online - Privacy Statement

Welcome to DISHNetwork.com, a service of DISH Network and its subsidiaries (collectively, "DISH Network," "we," or "us"). This statement discloses the privacy practices for this web site only.

## Children

DISH Network does not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of thirteen and does not wish to collect any such information.

## Information Collection and Use

The information collected by DISH Network falls into two categories: (1) information voluntarily supplied by visitors to and users of the web site and (2) tracking information recorded as visitors and users navigate through the web site. Some of this information is personally identifiable information, but much of it is not. Personally identifiable information is information that identifies a particular person.

To make use of some features on our web site, for example, in order to process requests for new service or make changes to existing service, visitors need to register and provide certain information as part of the registration process. We may ask, for example, for your name, email address, street address, zip code, and credit card or financial account information. We might also request information about your residence and number of televisions. Supplying this information is entirely voluntary, but if you choose not to supply the information, we may be unable to provide you with the products and services we make available to other users of and visitors to our web site. You will not be able to order selected products or services or automate payments over our web site unless you provide certain personally identifiable information about yourself.

When you submit any personally identifiable information over this web site, DISH Network (i) will use the information for the purposes described at the time you submit it, and (ii) may use the information to contact you to make you aware of other products and services of interest. Of course, if you want to remain completely anonymous, you're still free to take advantage of the publicly available content on our web site without registration.

Aggregate reports for web site visitors are also generated to measure the performance of DISH Network web sites. These reports do not contain any personally identifiable information.

When an individual visits any Internet site, a unique address called an "IP address" is recorded. DISH Network does not release any information about the collection of this address to any third party except under court order. DISH Network archives the log files in order to create aggregate statistical reports, detect errors at the web site, and for security reasons.

IP reports for advertisement clicks are shared with the advertiser and advertising networks. This information may be stored in DISH Network databases and/or those of advertisers and advertising networks. However, advertisers usually have this information already since their server captures it when a person clicks on an ad. This is done to verify billing for the ads. No additional information associated with any specific user is provided to advertisers.

In connection with the standard operation of DISH Network's systems, certain non-personally identifiable information about visitors to this web site is recorded. This information is used primarily to tailor and enhance visitors' experience using the web site. We may use this information in an aggregate, non- personally identifiable form to, among other things, measure the use of our web site and determine which products and services are the most popular with web site visitors.

## Disclosure of Personally Identifiable Information

We consider the personally identifiable information contained in our business records to be confidential. We may sometimes disclose personally identifiable information about you when it is necessary to render or conduct a legitimate business activity related to the services we provide to you. We may also disclose personally identifiable information about you to our affiliates or to others who work for us, such as service providers and vendors when it is necessary to render or conduct a legitimate business activity related to the services we provide to you. We may be required by law or legal process to disclose certain personally identifiable information about you to lawyers and parties in connection with litigation and to law enforcement personnel. For example, we may be required by law to disclose personally identifiable information about you without your consent and without notice in order to comply with a valid legal process such as a subpoena, court order, or search warrant.

## Cookies

Internet "cookies" may be used to customize our web site to the viewer. A cookie is a standard feature of browser software. Cookies help us tailor and personalize our web site. These cookies remain on the user's system and are automatically retrieved when a user visits at a later time. These cookies contain only information concerning the type of customer (current or potential) and frequently visited pages. No other personal information is stored on cookies.

Cookies may also be placed on the user's system by an Internet advertising network in order to track the viewing of banner ads displayed on DISH Network web sites. Since it is not necessary for a person to identify him or herself, cookies cannot be associated with an individual who selects not to log in or identify him or herself in any other way.

Customers who are still uncomfortable with the use of cookies have the option of disabling them on their browser. DISH Network in no way discriminates against web site visitors who have disabled cookies on their browser .

## Opting Out of Promotional Email

When first logging into My Account or the Customer Support Center, or when purchasing a system online, among other things, you will be directed to set up your preferences.

If you indicate that it is okay for DISH Network to contact you via email, we will use your email address to send you information about the topics you have selected. You can cancel this service at any time by logging into My Account, selecting Edit Online Information, selecting Edit My Preferences, and de-selecting the appropriate boxes. Please note, however, even if you opt-out of receiving news, offers, or other communications via email from us, if you are a DISH Network subscriber, we may contact you via email from time to time regarding issues with your subscriber account.

If you indicate that it is okay to contact you via email with news from DISH Network Partners, we may share your contact information with partner organizations that may then email you information concerning their products and services. You can cancel this service at any time by logging into My Account, selecting Edit Online Information, selecting Edit My Preferences, and de-selecting the appropriate box.

If you have a concern regarding our email policy write us at [feedback@customermail.dishnetwork.com.](mailto:feedback@customermail.dishnetwork.com)

## Other web sites

To make our web site more valuable to our visitors, we may offer some features in conjunction with other providers. Our web site may also include links to other web sites whose privacy policies and practices may differ from ours. Once you leave our web site by linking to another one, the use of any information you provide is governed by the privacy policy of the operator of the web site you're visiting. We recommend that you read the privacy policy of other web sites.

## Security

All information gathered on our web site is stored within an DISH Network database accessible only to DISH Network and its specifically authorized contractors and vendors. However, we cannot guarantee the complete security of our database, nor can we guarantee that information you supply won't be intercepted while being transmitted to us over the Internet.

## Changes to this Privacy Statement

We may change this privacy statement from time to time. If we change this privacy statement at some point in the future, we will post the changes on our web site and by continuing to use the web site after we post any changes, you accept and agree to this privacy statement, as modified.

## Privacy Policy for DISH Network Subscribers

This privacy statement discloses the privacy practices for this web site only. We supply a copy of the privacy notice that applies to our DBS subscribers separately. You may view that privacy notice anytime at www.dishnetwork.com by clicking on the "Subscriber Privacy Notice" link at the bottom of the homepage.

Version: February 2011
